<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Front End on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/front-end/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Front End on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub Pages.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 16:57:30 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/front-end/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autosaving with Vuex</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/autosaving-with-vuex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 16:57:30 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/autosaving-with-vuex/</guid>
      <description>Some background Back in the early 2000s, if you&amp;rsquo;d been working on a Microsoft Word document and shut down your computer without hitting Ctrl+S, you were in a bad spot. All your work was gone and there was no way to get it back. In future versions of Word they introduced an autorecovery tool, which if you were lucky would offer to get most of it back for you. That was nice, but the real game changer was Google Docs, with its always-vigilant Saved indicator, noticing whenever you changed the document and saving it to the cloud automatically every couple of seconds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 CSS gotchas to start your morning off right</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/8-css-gotchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 18:04:19 +0000</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/8-css-gotchas/</guid>
      <description>In every community there’s a coming-of-age process, a rite of passage that every newcomer must experience before he or she can really be considered an insider. For the CSS community, it goes something like this:&#xA;Hey, this page is almost perfect. Can you just center that icon vertically? I told the boss we can roll it live in five minutes.&#xA;For CSS junkies like me, lines like this provoke an involuntary nervous giggle, the kind of giggle you’ll hear if I tell you about the first time I got dumped or crashed my car.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
