<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>product on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/categories/product/</link>
    <description>Recent content in product on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub Pages.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 11:51:53 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://isaaclyman.com/blog/categories/product/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A keyboard is not a list of buttons</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/keyboard-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 11:51:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/keyboard-buttons/</guid>
      <description>Building a software keyboard is almost always a Bad Idea. The keyboards that come installed with our phones and tablets represent years of institutional knowledge and are fine-tuned for user experience and accessibility. A good keyboard is something you never have to think about, and it takes a significant investment to get there.
However, there are cases where you have no choice but to render your own. For example, in my mobile word game Sootly, each key on the keyboard has an animated, multi-color background representing clues for the puzzle you&amp;rsquo;re solving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidal vs Spotify: a music-lover&#39;s comparison</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/tidal-vs-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 11:25:43 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/tidal-vs-spotify/</guid>
      <description>During the recent Joe Rogan backlash I decided to cast a vote with my wallet and end my Spotify subscription. This concluded a nearly decade-long relationship between Spotify and me; I was one of their first North American users. I vividly remember having to snipe an invite code from page 7 of a forum thread back in 2011 so I could join the U.S. beta.
2011-era Spotify was pretty fantastic. The UX was really smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginner&#39;s Guide to Edward</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/edward-beginners-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 13:49:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/edward-beginners-guide/</guid>
      <description>If this is your first day with Edward, welcome! Edward is eager to help you write your first book. He specializes in novels, but is also a good choice for non-fiction, essays, poems and articles &amp;ndash; just keep in mind that some tools may not be as helpful.
This post will introduce you to Edward&amp;rsquo;s major features.
Edward has these main pages:
Plan A plan is a set of general notes that you&amp;rsquo;ll want to refer back to as you write your book, no matter which chapter you&amp;rsquo;re working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Edward the App</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/introducing-edward-write-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 13:08:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/introducing-edward-write-better/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Edward is a web app designed to help aspiring authors write their first novel.
It all started with a simple question: what if word processors are the worst possible apps for writing novels?
Take Microsoft Word, for example. It has a lot of formatting and layout tools. Bold, italic, multiple columns, 3D leopard-print text, it&amp;rsquo;s all included.
But you have to know what you want to write with those 3D words, and that&amp;rsquo;s your real problem anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
