<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unserious on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/tags/unserious/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unserious on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub Pages.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:59:02 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://isaaclyman.com/blog/tags/unserious/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Things I didn&#39;t know were different until I saw them next to each other</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/different/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:59:02 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/different/</guid>
      <description>You know how sometimes when you don&amp;rsquo;t pay enough attention, two similar but not identical things will occupy the same space in your brain? And you&amp;rsquo;ll go along thinking they&amp;rsquo;re the same until you&amp;rsquo;re 30 years old and see them in the same sentence and suddenly realize they&amp;rsquo;re not the same at all?&#xA;Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve never had this problem. I might not be playing with a full deck.&#xA;Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s a list of all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been surprised to find out are different.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 CSS gotchas to start your morning off right</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/8-css-gotchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 18:04:19 +0000</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/8-css-gotchas/</guid>
      <description>In every community there’s a coming-of-age process, a rite of passage that every newcomer must experience before he or she can really be considered an insider. For the CSS community, it goes something like this:&#xA;Hey, this page is almost perfect. Can you just center that icon vertically? I told the boss we can roll it live in five minutes.&#xA;For CSS junkies like me, lines like this provoke an involuntary nervous giggle, the kind of giggle you’ll hear if I tell you about the first time I got dumped or crashed my car.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If doctors were like coders</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/if-doctors-were-like-coders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 23:38:27 +0000</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/if-doctors-were-like-coders/</guid>
      <description>Problem The patient has a broken leg.&#xA;Solution Ask the patient to reproduce the exact scenario that resulted in the broken leg. Watch closely to see if the leg breaks again. Check for consistency by repeating the scenario a few more times. Explain that this isn’t an intended use case for the leg, and besides, it only affects one person. Ask the patient if, all things considered, he really wants to prioritize his broken leg over your other work.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
