<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Construction on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/software-construction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Construction on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub Pages.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 08:22:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/software-construction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Load testing with Jmeter: an introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/load-testing-jmeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 08:22:35 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/load-testing-jmeter/</guid>
      <description>Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to go from 0 to a configurable load testing script using JMeter, a free and popular load testing tool. We&amp;rsquo;ll be moving quickly, so hold on tight.&#xA;What is load testing? If your app or service is very successful, hundreds of people might be using it at once. Lots of things can go wrong when a server is under heavy usage like that. It&amp;rsquo;s not economical to recruit hundreds of actual people to test your app manually, so your best choice is to use software to simulate it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application environments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/application-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 16:17:12 -0600</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/application-environments/</guid>
      <description>What are environments, anyway? Most software companies have their product deployed to a few different environments, which have names like local, dev, test, stage, and production. On my first day as a developer I was confused about why there were so many steps between a developer&amp;rsquo;s computer and the app that customers used. It seemed inefficient and bureaucratic. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to appreciate those environments, though, and these days I break out in an ice-cold sweat if someone talks about deploying straight to production.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
