<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/categories/self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 10:13:55 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://isaaclyman.com/blog/categories/self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The 10 burger commandments</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/10-burger-commandments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 10:13:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/10-burger-commandments/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten a lot of bottom-tier burgers in my life and I&amp;rsquo;ve heartily enjoyed most of them. Neighborhood cookouts, college parties, church functions, fast food joints: throughout my life, bad burgers have been a mainstay of the public spaces I frequent. And if the suburban United States is home to you, you know exactly what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. A soft grocery-store bun; an iPhone-thin patty of bland, meat-like grind, cooked well-done on a gas grill; a pasty, out-of-season tomato slice; a rag of wilted lettuce; a few strings of raw onion; and a splotch of lukewarm ketchup and mustard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Parents</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/good-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 16:47:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/good-parents/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes when people think I&amp;rsquo;ve done a good thing, they&amp;rsquo;ll say something like &amp;ldquo;you must have wonderful parents,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;ve been raised well.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m against this kind of statement for two reasons.
1 It submits that the worth of my parents&amp;rsquo; sacrifices can be measured by the way I turned out. This is unfair to them. If I had turned out to be a bad person, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t change the value of what they did; obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t invalidate their efforts by intentionally becoming a failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile in real life</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/agile-in-real-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 09:26:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/agile-in-real-life/</guid>
      <description>Most people follow the Waterfall development methodology when building a new habit:
 Determine the end goal and deadline (e.g. I will lose 40 pounds by 2019). Write the goal down. Design the habits that will lead up to that goal (e.g. I will stop eating anything that tastes good, and I will exercise five times a week). Assemble the necessary motivations (e.g. accountability buddy, FitBit, bathroom scale, gym membership, workout routine, diet plan).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>