<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resume on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/tags/resume/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resume on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 08:02:55 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://isaaclyman.com/blog/tags/resume/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m writing a book for junior developers!</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/im-writing-a-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 08:02:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/im-writing-a-book/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing a book: a complete guide to your first year as a developer. And I&amp;rsquo;m looking for co-authors.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a technical manual about Python or Kubernetes or Angular. And it&amp;rsquo;s not a deep-dive about refactoring or craftsmanship. It&amp;rsquo;s a guide to the other stuff: resume writing, getting that first job, ethics, career progression, what to do when you&amp;rsquo;re stuck.
The book will be pay-what-you-want (minimum price of free).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing a job title</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/choosing-a-job-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 13:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/choosing-a-job-title/</guid>
      <description>Are you a coder, programmer, developer, engineer, architect or something else? My first job was an underage, under-the-table weekend gig at a pizza parlor. I’d show up at the local strip mall early Saturday morning, stash my bike, and clock in. For me, the work was grueling. I would haul 50-pound bags of flour and 10-gallon buckets of water to a giant stand mixer, and once it finished spinning I’d lift armfuls of incredibly heavy dough to a metal table where I’d cut and oil portions weighed for each size of pizza that the shop sold.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>