<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>science on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/categories/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in science on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub Pages.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:34:59 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://isaaclyman.com/blog/categories/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What I want my friends to know about drugs</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/about-drugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:34:59 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/about-drugs/</guid>
      <description>I am not a doctor and this is not medical advice. Consult your doctor before using any drug.
In the United States, LSD and heroin are in the same controlled substance category (the most restrictive one, Schedule I), placing them a category above amphetamines and fentanyl, two categories above ketamine, and three full categories above alprazolam (Xanax). Tobacco is not a controlled substance at all. I hope to convince you that this is ridiculous—not merely an outdated or insufficiently-nuanced classification system, but one so wrong it can only have been created by rolling dice or throwing darts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stimulant medication and heart health</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/stimulants-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 09:52:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/stimulants-heart/</guid>
      <description>Central nervous system stimulants such as Adderall, Ritalin, and Vyvanse are commonly used to treat ADHD and narcolepsy in children and adults. Common side effects of these drugs are increased blood pressure and heart rate. Anecdotally, many patients and doctors assume that there are negative long-term heart consequences for stimulant use, even when taken as prescribed and in approved doses. The purpose of this article is to review the available research and determine if this concern is supported by the evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments with water, a scale, and a rubber duck</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/archimedes-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 10:18:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/archimedes-experiment/</guid>
      <description>I did some science experiments this morning, and I&amp;rsquo;m here to share my results. The experiments ultimately failed to produce any good data, but I think the process was interesting anyway.
Background I was making pizza dough this week, which for me is a process involving a kitchen scale, a thermometer, and a three-day cold ferment. I always start with a bowl on a scale and add water, kosher salt, sugar, and yeast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
