<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 21:51:52 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://isaaclyman.com/blog/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>If you don&#39;t hire juniors, you don&#39;t deserve seniors</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/junior-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 21:51:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/junior-developers/</guid>
      <description>Let me tell you the story of a very successful company that made a very big, dumb decision.
 We don&amp;rsquo;t hire junior developers or interns&amp;hellip;if you don&amp;rsquo;t get a puppy, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to clean up its messes.
~ Netflix
 I&amp;rsquo;m flabbergasted that some corporate schmuck figured out a way to cast puppies in a negative light and people kept listening. I mean, puppies are the purest beings on planet Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A future without time zones</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/time-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 08:44:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/time-zones/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re a software engineer living in Idaho. You wake up with the sun at 2PM, Greenwich Mean Time, which everyone just calls &amp;ldquo;UN Time&amp;rdquo; since the United Nations adopted it as the universal time standard a few years ago. Soon nobody will call it anything. That&amp;rsquo;ll just be what time it is. Regardless of whether you&amp;rsquo;re in Idaho, DC, Ireland, Nepal or New Zealand, all the clocks will say 2:00 PM at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you&#39;re stuck</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/stuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 08:28:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/stuck/</guid>
      <description>This is a chapter from Your First Year in Code, a book of practical how-to and advice for new developers. If you&amp;rsquo;re considering a career in software, check it out. It&amp;rsquo;s a free download at https://leanpub.com/firstyearincode.
 Part of a programmer&amp;rsquo;s job is chasing down missing semicolons and complex caching issues, scrutinizing and head-scratching over every line of code in an application. This is one of the most frustrating things about code: we use it to offload complexity from our brains, but the inverse of this benefit is that any useful program will be too complex for us to wrap our minds around completely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile in real life</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/agile-in-real-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 09:26:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/agile-in-real-life/</guid>
      <description>Most people follow the Waterfall development methodology when building a new habit:
 Determine the end goal and deadline (e.g. I will lose 40 pounds by 2019). Write the goal down. Design the habits that will lead up to that goal (e.g. I will stop eating anything that tastes good, and I will exercise five times a week). Assemble the necessary motivations (e.g. accountability buddy, FitBit, bathroom scale, gym membership, workout routine, diet plan).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
