<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Religion on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/categories/religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Religion on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub Pages.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 20:01:25 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/categories/religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On belief, performance, and effect</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/planet-of-belief/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 20:01:25 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/planet-of-belief/</guid>
      <description>What do people actually mean when they say they &amp;ldquo;believe&amp;rdquo; a particular religion? There are likely many factions we incorrectly group as one because they use the same term.&#xA;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;ve set out on a space journey as humanity&amp;rsquo;s first envoy to the stars. You arrive on an inhabited planet and meet the locals. As soon as you&amp;rsquo;ve worked out mutual communication, the first thing you discover is their religious beliefs mirror yours exactly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problems for transgender-excluding Mormons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problems-for-transgender-excluding-mormons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:58:32 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problems-for-transgender-excluding-mormons/</guid>
      <description>I grew up in the Mormon church, performed Mormon missionary service, and studied at a Mormon university. Though I no longer identify with the church, my understanding of Mormonism is not dysfunctional.&#xA;Many or most Mormons see their belief system as incompatible with transgender acceptance. On the contrary, I believe the Mormon church is well-positioned, perhaps better than any other Christian sect, to understand and include transgender people.&#xA;For those who are reluctant to allow transgender experiences into their belief system, I present a few problems that any transgender-excluding Mormon must resolve.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your annual &#39;Am I in a cult?&#39; checkup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/your-annual-cult-checkup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 13:44:30 -0600</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/your-annual-cult-checkup/</guid>
      <description>Consider this:&#xA;Most cult members don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;re in a cult. You don&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;re in a cult. Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s possible you&amp;rsquo;re in a cult. Now, I have no reason to suspect that anyone I know is in a cult. The elephant in the room here is Mormonism, the religion I was raised in, and honestly I think some Mormons are cultists and others are not. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that one for people to decide on their own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When religion fails us</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/when-religion-fails-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 13:49:57 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/when-religion-fails-us/</guid>
      <description>** - Religion fails us when we&#xA;** - Religion fails us when we give up our own personal moral authority.**&#xA;Moral authority is the right to say something is good or evil. This is something we&amp;rsquo;re all born with; it&amp;rsquo;s an essential component of moral agency. In some cases we may be wrong or knowingly choose to do evil,&#xA;** - Religion fails us when we tread on one principle in service of another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On romance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/on-romance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 14:09:58 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/on-romance/</guid>
      <description>It seems to me that there are four pillars of romantic life:&#xA;Attraction Love (i.e. &amp;ldquo;in love,&amp;rdquo; not &amp;ldquo;love ya, mom&amp;rdquo;) Physical intimacy Commitment (e.g. exclusivity, marriage) There&amp;rsquo;s a tendency to think of them as a package deal, but on deeper inspection, they&amp;rsquo;re clearly separate. Any of them can exist without the others.&#xA;Attraction only: A foundational human experience. You find a person attractive, but for reasons of decency, nerves, loyalty, intuition, or good judgment, you do nothing about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So let it be with Caesar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/so-let-it-be-with-caesar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 08:58:19 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/so-let-it-be-with-caesar/</guid>
      <description>The evil that men do lives after them; the good is oft interred with their bones. So let it be with Caesar.&#xA;~ Shakespeare, &amp;ldquo;Julius Caesar&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Grok, if you can, the utter inability of human beings to describe other human beings neutrally. Almost all adjectives, even the most objective, become a value judgment when used to label a person&amp;mdash;words like &amp;ldquo;short&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;plump&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;withdrawn&amp;rdquo; invoke an emotional response in many readers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America needs a new Republican party</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/america-needs-a-new-republican-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 12:19:02 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/america-needs-a-new-republican-party/</guid>
      <description>I’m a white man by birth and a Christian by heritage. I’m also a Democrat (technically unaffiliated, but only as an escape hatch). What’s more, I believe that I’m a Democrat because of my Christian heritage and beliefs, not in spite of them. It’s clear to me that the left side of America’s political divide most closely (albeit imperfectly) embodies the ideals of Judeo-Christian morality.&#xA;I feel a need to justify myself in this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Several bad reasons to believe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/several-bad-reasons-to-believe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 12:15:45 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/several-bad-reasons-to-believe/</guid>
      <description>There are two things you need to know about the Internet: It promotes good ideas, and it promotes bad ideas. The tight, homogeneous communities you’ll find online are echo chambers that use confirmation bias and positive feedback loops to make every answer to every question — wrong or right — much louder and more cliche. The relative stupidity or genius of any one statement rarely has anything to do with its spread or influence.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
