<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>development on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in development on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub Pages.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 08:50:34 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://isaaclyman.com/blog/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is code a performative speech act?</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/code-performative-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 08:50:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/code-performative-speech/</guid>
      <description>Computer processing is the act by which the world of the computer is constructed. We can call it a world because it appears to exist unto itself, persisting its environment and taking scripted actions well outside of our awareness. Modern computers rarely shut off completely, so the illusion of persistence (&amp;ldquo;my user desktop is still there even when my computer is asleep; I just drop in on it now and then&amp;rdquo;) is not entirely an illusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C#: Equality overrides, hash codes, and dictionaries</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/csharp-dictionary-hashcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 14:22:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/csharp-dictionary-hashcode/</guid>
      <description>Consider the following C# class:
class StringEquivalent { private string Value { get; } public StringEquivalent(string value) { Value = value; } public override string ToString() { return Value; } public override bool Equals(object obj) { if (obj == null) { return false; } return obj.ToString() == Value; } public override int GetHashCode() { return Value.GetHashCode(); } } You provide a string when you instantiate it and you can compare it with another instance or a string using the Equals override (I&amp;rsquo;m using LINQPad&amp;rsquo;s Dump() method to test it):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YAML Pipelines in Azure DevOps: tips and advice</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/ado-yaml-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:02:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/ado-yaml-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>Classic pipelines are out, YAML pipelines are in. Azure DevOps (ADO) has adopted a pipelines-as-code philosophy that will be their build and release strategy for the foreseeable future. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to appreciate about the new pipelines, though they are a bit of a mental adjustment and the transition is anything but automatic&amp;mdash;I took a few weeks converting all of ours, though there were some special obstacles in our case that hopefully you won&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost AirPods, arrays, and sorting algorithms</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/sorting-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 20:09:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/sorting-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>The search for the lost AirPod My wife Dylan is a math and physics teacher. Yesterday while she was on a Zoom call with a student I got a text message from her: &amp;ldquo;the kids have my AirPods.&amp;rdquo; She knew because her student was cracking up laughing at the babblings of our toddlers, captured by the built-in microphone on the AirPods.
I tracked down the kids. They were carrying around an AirPod case with one AirPod in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C#: IEnumerable, yield return, and lazy evaluation</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/csharp-ienumerable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 10:13:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/csharp-ienumerable/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about one of my favorite .NET features.
IEnumerable is an interface for iterating over a collection. In other words, if something is an IEnumerable, you can mostly think of it like an Array or a List. You can use a foreach statement to loop through it, you can use LINQ to map or reduce it in a hundred different ways, or you can explicitly cast it to an array with .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load testing with Jmeter: an introduction</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/load-testing-jmeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 08:22:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/load-testing-jmeter/</guid>
      <description>Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to go from 0 to a configurable load testing script using JMeter, a free and popular load testing tool. We&amp;rsquo;ll be moving quickly, so hold on tight.
What is load testing? If your app or service is very successful, hundreds of people might be using it at once. Lots of things can go wrong when a server is under heavy usage like that. It&amp;rsquo;s not economical to recruit hundreds of actual people to test your app manually, so your best choice is to use software to simulate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to learn first</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/what-to-learn-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 09:01:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/what-to-learn-first/</guid>
      <description>This is a chapter from Your First Year in Code, a book of practical how-to and advice for new developers. If you&amp;rsquo;re considering a career in software, check it out. It&amp;rsquo;s a free download at https://leanpub.com/firstyearincode.
I occasionally get a message from a brand-new developer who&amp;rsquo;s overwhelmed by all the technologies and choices that exist in the world of software development. Where do you even start? Some of these devs have seen job advertisements like the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is how HTTPS works</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/https/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 07:00:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/https/</guid>
      <description>Most people are familiar with the http:// that begins web site URLs. And some may have noticed that any website with a login form or sensitive information starts with https:// instead. The &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo; stands for &amp;ldquo;Secure,&amp;rdquo; and the algorithms that make it work are crazy and wonderful. To understand why HTTPS is so magical, let&amp;rsquo;s use an analogy.
Suppose you gather three accomplished programmers: Janice, Natalia, and Mario. These three have never met or communicated in any way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you&#39;re stuck</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/stuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 08:28:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/stuck/</guid>
      <description>This is a chapter from Your First Year in Code, a book of practical how-to and advice for new developers. If you&amp;rsquo;re considering a career in software, check it out. It&amp;rsquo;s a free download at https://leanpub.com/firstyearincode.
Part of a programmer&amp;rsquo;s job is chasing down missing semicolons and complex caching issues, scrutinizing and head-scratching over every line of code in an application. This is one of the most frustrating things about code: we use it to offload complexity from our brains, but the inverse of this benefit is that any useful program will be too complex for us to wrap our minds around completely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application environments</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/application-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 16:17:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/application-environments/</guid>
      <description>What are environments, anyway? Most software companies have their product deployed to a few different environments, which have names like local, dev, test, stage, and production. On my first day as a developer I was confused about why there were so many steps between a developer&amp;rsquo;s computer and the app that customers used. It seemed inefficient and bureaucratic. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to appreciate those environments, though, and these days I break out in an ice-cold sweat if someone talks about deploying straight to production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autosaving with Vuex</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/autosaving-with-vuex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 16:57:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/autosaving-with-vuex/</guid>
      <description>Some background Back in the early 2000s, if you&amp;rsquo;d been working on a Microsoft Word document and shut down your computer without hitting Ctrl+S, you were in a bad spot. All your work was gone and there was no way to get it back. In future versions of Word they introduced an autorecovery tool, which if you were lucky would offer to get most of it back for you. That was nice, but the real game changer was Google Docs, with its always-vigilant Saved indicator, noticing whenever you changed the document and saving it to the cloud automatically every couple of seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privilege by mail</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/privilege-by-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 09:56:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/privilege-by-mail/</guid>
      <description>Leer en español
I feel very privileged to lead the life I lead. I live in a good neighborhood. I can change jobs if I don&amp;rsquo;t like the one I have. I haven&amp;rsquo;t worried about how to pay for groceries since 2013. If I were to list all my blessings, I could go on forever&amp;mdash;but in short, I lead a far better life than I deserve and I&amp;rsquo;m anything but self-made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyman&#39;s Law</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/lymans-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 06:54:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/lymans-law/</guid>
      <description>A pretty-darned-optional part of being a software developer is getting a generally-applicable principle (a &amp;ldquo;law&amp;rdquo;) named after yourself. Most of the time, it seems, this happens unintentionally&amp;ndash;the law&amp;rsquo;s originator doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily foresee it becoming a pithy and oft-repeated internet adage. But if I could choose a principle to call &amp;ldquo;Lyman&amp;rsquo;s Law,&amp;rdquo; I think it might be this one:
Code accompanied by unit tests will have a higher standard of code quality than code written without unit tests, even if the unit tests themselves are not taken into account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steps to better code</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/steps-to-better-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 14:01:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/steps-to-better-code/</guid>
      <description>This is a chapter from Your First Year in Code, a book of practical how-to and advice for new developers. If you&amp;rsquo;re considering a career in software, check it out. It&amp;rsquo;s a free download at https://leanpub.com/firstyearincode.
When you start out coding, you usually spend a year or two completely oblivious to the rules of “good code.” You may hear words like “elegant” or “clean” tossed around, but you can’t define them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
