<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub Pages.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 09:51:52 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://isaaclyman.com/blog/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>If you don&#39;t hire juniors, you don&#39;t deserve seniors (2023)</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/junior-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 09:51:52 -0600</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/junior-developers/</guid>
      <description>This was originally written in 2018. It remains one of my more popular blog posts, so I&amp;rsquo;ve taken some time to revise it to match the current market environment and my evolving opinions on the topic.&#xA;Let me tell you the story of a very successful company that made a very big, dumb decision.&#xA;We don&amp;rsquo;t hire junior developers or interns&amp;hellip;if you don&amp;rsquo;t get a puppy, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to clean up its messes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leadership and motivation</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/what-people-hear/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 09:06:51 -0600</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/what-people-hear/</guid>
      <description>One of the core hard things about leadership is that people hear what they are, not what you say.&#xA;When you say “let’s work hard and get this done,” you’re probably hoping to light a fire under the easygoing or underachieving members of the team, but only the anxious, hardworking folks who are already at risk for burnout will hear you. And when you say “but pace yourself and take breaks” you’re hoping to bring the overachievers down a notch but that won&amp;rsquo;t work; laid-back people will take this as a cue to lay back even more and their anxious teammates will try to pick up the slack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring in tech? Don&#39;t compete on price</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/dont-compete-on-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 09:11:11 -0600</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/dont-compete-on-price/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a strong business case&amp;mdash;a financially sound, common-sense case&amp;mdash;for acquiring tech talent such as developers, designers, product managers, and QA engineers using quality-of-life values instead of competing on compensation. Conversations about this topic have been taking place in online developer communities for years, but it seems these ideas haven&amp;rsquo;t penetrated the larger tech and business world. If you read on, you&amp;rsquo;ll find there&amp;rsquo;s a wealth of compelling evidence in favor of offering shorter workdays and remote options to your employees as a hiring and loyalty incentive, rather than trying to out-pay the market.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting a business for your app</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/starting-a-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 11:11:40 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/starting-a-business/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I am not a lawyer and this is not legal advice. Before starting a business, you should consult your own lawyer.&#xA;We developers are uniquely positioned to start our own companies. I don&amp;rsquo;t mean to downplay the importance of managers, accountants, salespeople, and everyone else who makes a business come together, but devs bring something very rare to the table: the ability to call forth an entire high-value product from the abyss, using no raw materials whatsoever.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
