<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kryptos on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/tags/kryptos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kryptos on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub Pages.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 09:20:46 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://isaaclyman.com/blog/tags/kryptos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Solving the CIA Kryptos code in TypeScript (Part 4)</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/kryptos-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 09:20:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/kryptos-4/</guid>
      <description>You can find all the code for this series on GitHub.
Kryptos 4 is, I repeat, unsolved. We&amp;rsquo;re very unlikely to solve it today. Enthusiastic codebreakers have been putting together clues and proposing theories for decades. At least half of them are like this:
But hey, since we&amp;rsquo;ve got some code ready to go, we might as well try.
Setup All the code we&amp;rsquo;ve written so far is available on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving the CIA Kryptos code in TypeScript (Part 3)</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/kryptos-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 09:15:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/kryptos-3/</guid>
      <description>You can find all the code for this series on GitHub.
Kryptos 3 is going to require more code than anything else so far. It&amp;rsquo;s encoded using both the types of transposition we covered in Part 2, plus a twist.
It&amp;rsquo;s written out with a rectangle size of 86 and a block size of 7. The columns are stacked. A keyed columnar cipher is applied with the key &amp;lsquo;KRYPTOS&amp;rsquo;. (KRYPTOS is seven characters long, which is why our block size is 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving the CIA Kryptos code in TypeScript (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/kryptos-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 09:11:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/kryptos-2/</guid>
      <description>You can find all the code for this series on GitHub.
In the previous post we solved Kryptos 1 and 2. Kryptos 3 is going to be a bit tougher. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t use our trusty Vigenere cipher. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t use just one cipher, either; it uses two. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn them separately in this post, then use them together in the next one.
Keyed columnar transposition We need to learn a transposition cipher, which is where the letters in a message are rearranged but not changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving the CIA Kryptos code in TypeScript (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/kryptos-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 09:05:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/kryptos-1/</guid>
      <description>You can find all the code for this series on GitHub.
On the campus of CIA headquarters in Virginia, United States, there&amp;rsquo;s a 34-year-old sculpture called Kryptos. It somewhat resembles a heavy copper flag waving in the wind. Cut out of its surface are 1,736 uppercase ASCII characters split into four encrypted messages and a Vigenere cipher table.
The first three messages were decrypted in the 1990s, first by the NSA and CIA, who didn&amp;rsquo;t publicize their success, and then by a private-sector computer scientist, who did.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
