<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Satire on Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/categories/satire/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Satire on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub Pages.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 10:06:11 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/categories/satire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New tech terms to learn in 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/tech-terms-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 10:06:11 -0700</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/tech-terms-2022/</guid>
      <description>Ad-hocumentation Good documentation is a developer&amp;rsquo;s best friend, and some products and tools have truly excellent docs because they pay people to maintain them. When you Google a library method and the first result is an official, up-to-date web page with a description, code sample, use cases, limitations, and type information&amp;mdash;all written and maintained by an actual human being? That&amp;rsquo;s paradise, my friend. Much of the time we&amp;rsquo;re not so lucky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 CSS gotchas to start your morning off right</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/8-css-gotchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 18:04:19 +0000</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/8-css-gotchas/</guid>
      <description>In every community there’s a coming-of-age process, a rite of passage that every newcomer must experience before he or she can really be considered an insider. For the CSS community, it goes something like this:&#xA;Hey, this page is almost perfect. Can you just center that icon vertically? I told the boss we can roll it live in five minutes.&#xA;For CSS junkies like me, lines like this provoke an involuntary nervous giggle, the kind of giggle you’ll hear if I tell you about the first time I got dumped or crashed my car.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If doctors were like coders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/if-doctors-were-like-coders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 23:38:27 +0000</pubDate><author>map[host:isaaclyman.com username:blog] (Isaac Lyman)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/if-doctors-were-like-coders/</guid>
      <description>Problem The patient has a broken leg.&#xA;Solution Ask the patient to reproduce the exact scenario that resulted in the broken leg. Watch closely to see if the leg breaks again. Check for consistency by repeating the scenario a few more times. Explain that this isn’t an intended use case for the leg, and besides, it only affects one person. Ask the patient if, all things considered, he really wants to prioritize his broken leg over your other work.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
