<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 12:43:55 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://isaaclyman.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The 24 most incredible things I&#39;ve ever eaten</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/mind-blowing-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 12:43:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/mind-blowing-food/</guid>
      <description>I would call this &amp;ldquo;24 incredible foods you need to eat before you die&amp;rdquo; but that template is overplayed and unnecessarily depressing, in my opinion. Yes, you should eat all of these if you have the chance. No, your life isn&amp;rsquo;t less-than if you don&amp;rsquo;t.
Feel free to leave a comment if I missed one of your favorites.
1 . Torta de chorizo con huevos Starting things off is a very simple Mexican sandwich made with paprika-flavored ground sausage, scrambled eggs, mayonnaise, and a football-shaped bread roll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some things to know before you learn Mandarin Chinese</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/things-to-know-chinese/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 15:26:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/things-to-know-chinese/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning Mandarin over the past two months and it&amp;rsquo;s been one surprise after another. I already speak English and Spanish, two languages that in retrospect are practically twins. Mandarin, on the other hand, comes not just from the opposite side of the globe but from the opposite side of the linguistic universe. As such, it&amp;rsquo;s a special sort of challenge for someone who speaks a Western language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load testing with Jmeter: an introduction</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/load-testing-jmeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 08:22:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/load-testing-jmeter/</guid>
      <description>Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to go from 0 to a configurable load testing script using JMeter, a free and popular load testing tool. We&amp;rsquo;ll be moving quickly, so hold on tight.
What is load testing? If your app or service is very successful, hundreds of people might be using it at once. Lots of things can go wrong when a server is under heavy usage like that. It&amp;rsquo;s not economical to recruit hundreds of actual people to test your app manually, so your best choice is to use software to simulate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 10 burger commandments</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/10-burger-commandments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 10:13:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/10-burger-commandments/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten a lot of bottom-tier burgers in my life and I&amp;rsquo;ve heartily enjoyed most of them. Neighborhood cookouts, college parties, church functions, fast food joints: throughout my life, bad burgers have been a mainstay of the public spaces I frequent. And if the suburban United States is home to you, you know exactly what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. A soft grocery-store bun; an iPhone-thin patty of bland, meat-like grind, cooked well-done on a gas grill; a pasty, out-of-season tomato slice; a rag of wilted lettuce; a few strings of raw onion; and a splotch of lukewarm ketchup and mustard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christian symbolism in Guardians of the Galaxy, Vol. 2</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/christian-symbolism-in-guardians/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 07:39:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/christian-symbolism-in-guardians/</guid>
      <description>While rewatching Guardians of the Galaxy, Vol. 2 last night, I was struck by the amount of unsubtle Christianity baked into the film. I have no history with the comics so I can&amp;rsquo;t trace this symbolism to its source as handily as I&amp;rsquo;d like (though I&amp;rsquo;m peripherally aware of Mantis being heralded as the mother-to-be of a &amp;ldquo;Celestial Messiah&amp;rdquo; in the original comic). But I can point out a few things that my liberal arts degree may attune me to sooner than the average movie-goer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m writing a book for junior developers!</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/im-writing-a-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 08:02:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/im-writing-a-book/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing a book: a complete guide to your first year as a developer. And I&amp;rsquo;m looking for co-authors.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a technical manual about Python or Kubernetes or Angular. And it&amp;rsquo;s not a deep-dive about refactoring or craftsmanship. It&amp;rsquo;s a guide to the other stuff: resume writing, getting that first job, ethics, career progression, what to do when you&amp;rsquo;re stuck.
The book will be pay-what-you-want (minimum price of free).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to learn first</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/what-to-learn-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 09:01:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/what-to-learn-first/</guid>
      <description>This is a chapter from Your First Year in Code, a book of practical how-to and advice for new developers. If you&amp;rsquo;re considering a career in software, check it out. It&amp;rsquo;s a free download at https://leanpub.com/firstyearincode.
I occasionally get a message from a brand-new developer who&amp;rsquo;s overwhelmed by all the technologies and choices that exist in the world of software development. Where do you even start? Some of these devs have seen job advertisements like the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you don&#39;t hire juniors, you don&#39;t deserve seniors</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/junior-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 21:51:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/junior-developers/</guid>
      <description>Let me tell you the story of a very successful company that made a very big, dumb decision.
 We don&amp;rsquo;t hire junior developers or interns&amp;hellip;if you don&amp;rsquo;t get a puppy, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to clean up its messes.
~ Netflix
 I&amp;rsquo;m flabbergasted that some corporate schmuck figured out a way to cast puppies in a negative light and people kept listening. I mean, puppies are the purest beings on planet Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is how HTTPS works</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/https/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 07:00:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/https/</guid>
      <description>Most people are familiar with the http:// that begins web site URLs. And some may have noticed that any website with a login form or sensitive information starts with https:// instead. The &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo; stands for &amp;ldquo;Secure,&amp;rdquo; and the algorithms that make it work are crazy and wonderful. To understand why HTTPS is so magical, let&amp;rsquo;s use an analogy.
Suppose you gather three accomplished programmers: Janice, Natalia, and Mario. These three have never met or communicated in any way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A future without time zones</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/time-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 08:44:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/time-zones/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re a software engineer living in Idaho. You wake up with the sun at 2PM, Greenwich Mean Time, which everyone just calls &amp;ldquo;UN Time&amp;rdquo; since the United Nations adopted it as the universal time standard a few years ago. Soon nobody will call it anything. That&amp;rsquo;ll just be what time it is. Regardless of whether you&amp;rsquo;re in Idaho, DC, Ireland, Nepal or New Zealand, all the clocks will say 2:00 PM at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiring in tech? Don&#39;t compete on price</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/dont-compete-on-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 09:11:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/dont-compete-on-price/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a strong business case&amp;mdash;a financially sound, common-sense case&amp;mdash;for acquiring tech talent such as developers, designers, product managers, and QA engineers using quality-of-life values instead of competing on compensation. Conversations about this topic have been taking place in online developer communities for years, but it seems these ideas haven&amp;rsquo;t penetrated the larger tech and business world. If you read on, you&amp;rsquo;ll find there&amp;rsquo;s a wealth of compelling evidence in favor of offering shorter workdays and remote options to your employees as a hiring and loyalty incentive, rather than trying to out-pay the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a business for your app</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/starting-a-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 11:11:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/starting-a-business/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I am not a lawyer and this is not legal advice. Before starting a business, you should consult your own lawyer.
We developers are uniquely positioned to start our own companies. I don&amp;rsquo;t mean to downplay the importance of managers, accountants, salespeople, and everyone else who makes a business come together, but devs bring something very rare to the table: the ability to call forth an entire high-value product from the abyss, using no raw materials whatsoever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Parents</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/good-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 16:47:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/good-parents/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes when people think I&amp;rsquo;ve done a good thing, they&amp;rsquo;ll say something like &amp;ldquo;you must have wonderful parents,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;ve been raised well.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m against this kind of statement for two reasons.
1 It submits that the worth of my parents&amp;rsquo; sacrifices can be measured by the way I turned out. This is unfair to them. If I had turned out to be a bad person, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t change the value of what they did; obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t invalidate their efforts by intentionally becoming a failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On opportunity and outcomes</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/on-opportunity-and-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 09:14:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/on-opportunity-and-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>A slogan I hear often in Utah is
 Equal opportunity, not equal outcomes.
 The Beehive State sees itself as a paradise of the American dream. There&amp;rsquo;s very little regulation, a strong preference for businesses over people, and a limited interest in welfare programs outside of Salt Lake City. When people parrot this slogan, they think they&amp;rsquo;re saying &amp;ldquo;if you work hard, you can succeed; if you&amp;rsquo;re lazy, no one&amp;rsquo;s going to give you a free ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you&#39;re stuck</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/stuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 08:28:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/stuck/</guid>
      <description>This is a chapter from Your First Year in Code, a book of practical how-to and advice for new developers. If you&amp;rsquo;re considering a career in software, check it out. It&amp;rsquo;s a free download at https://leanpub.com/firstyearincode.
Part of a programmer&amp;rsquo;s job is chasing down missing semicolons and complex caching issues, scrutinizing and head-scratching over every line of code in an application. This is one of the most frustrating things about code: we use it to offload complexity from our brains, but the inverse of this benefit is that any useful program will be too complex for us to wrap our minds around completely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application environments</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/application-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 16:17:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/application-environments/</guid>
      <description>What are environments, anyway? Most software companies have their product deployed to a few different environments, which have names like local, dev, test, stage, and production. On my first day as a developer I was confused about why there were so many steps between a developer&amp;rsquo;s computer and the app that customers used. It seemed inefficient and bureaucratic. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to appreciate those environments, though, and these days I break out in an ice-cold sweat if someone talks about deploying straight to production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autosaving with Vuex</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/autosaving-with-vuex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 16:57:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/autosaving-with-vuex/</guid>
      <description>Some background Back in the early 2000s, if you&amp;rsquo;d been working on a Microsoft Word document and shut down your computer without hitting Ctrl+S, you were in a bad spot. All your work was gone and there was no way to get it back. In future versions of Word they introduced an autorecovery tool, which if you were lucky would offer to get most of it back for you. That was nice, but the real game changer was Google Docs, with its always-vigilant Saved indicator, noticing whenever you changed the document and saving it to the cloud automatically every couple of seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About guns</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/about-guns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 16:32:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/about-guns/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a gun violence expert. Still, I care about guns for the same reason everyone does: people with guns are an imminent threat to the lives of people I care about. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it at the time, but there&amp;rsquo;s only one reason I never got shot by a stranger in high school: luck. And I hope that everyone I know has the same luck. But if there&amp;rsquo;s anything the last decade in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privilege by mail</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/privilege-by-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 09:56:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/privilege-by-mail/</guid>
      <description>Leer en español
I feel very privileged to lead the life I lead. I live in a good neighborhood. I can change jobs if I don&amp;rsquo;t like the one I have. I haven&amp;rsquo;t worried about how to pay for groceries since 2013. If I were to list all my blessings, I could go on forever&amp;mdash;but in short, I lead a far better life than I deserve and I&amp;rsquo;m anything but self-made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privilegio por correo</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/privilegio-por-correo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 09:56:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/privilegio-por-correo/</guid>
      <description>Read in English
Me siento bien privilegiado por llevar la vida que llevo. Vivo en un vecindario bueno. Si no me gusta un trabajo, me lo puedo cambiar. No me he preocupado por poder comprar comida desde 2013. Si yo hiciera una lista de mis bendiciones, pudiera seguir para siempre. Pero, en resumen, llevo una vida mucho mejor de lo que merezco, y no lo logré solo. Me abruma mirar hacia atrás y darme cuenta de las oportunidades que tenía por razón del lugar donde nací y quienes son mis padres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So let it be with Caesar</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/so-let-it-be-with-caesar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 08:58:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/so-let-it-be-with-caesar/</guid>
      <description>The evil that men do lives after them; the good is oft interred with their bones. So let it be with Caesar.
~ Shakespeare, &amp;ldquo;Julius Caesar&amp;rdquo;
 Grok, if you can, the utter inability of human beings to describe other human beings neutrally. Almost all adjectives, even the most objective, become a value judgment when used to label a person&amp;mdash;words like &amp;ldquo;short&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;plump&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;withdrawn&amp;rdquo; invoke an emotional response in many readers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginner&#39;s Guide to Edward</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/edward-beginners-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 13:49:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/edward-beginners-guide/</guid>
      <description>If this is your first day with Edward, welcome! Edward is eager to help you write your first book. He specializes in novels, but is also a good choice for non-fiction, essays, poems and articles &amp;ndash; just keep in mind that some tools may not be as helpful.
This post will introduce you to Edward&amp;rsquo;s major features.
Edward has these main pages:
 Plan  A plan is a set of general notes that you&amp;rsquo;ll want to refer back to as you write your book, no matter which chapter you&amp;rsquo;re working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Edward the App</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/introducing-edward-write-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 13:08:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/introducing-edward-write-better/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Edward is a web app designed to help aspiring authors write their first novel.
It all started with a simple question: what if word processors are the worst possible apps for writing novels?
Take Microsoft Word, for example. It has a lot of formatting and layout tools. Bold, italic, multiple columns, 3D leopard-print text, it&amp;rsquo;s all included.
But you have to know what you want to write with those 3D words, and that&amp;rsquo;s your real problem anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile in real life</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/agile-in-real-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 09:26:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/agile-in-real-life/</guid>
      <description>Most people follow the Waterfall development methodology when building a new habit:
 Determine the end goal and deadline (e.g. I will lose 40 pounds by 2019). Write the goal down. Design the habits that will lead up to that goal (e.g. I will stop eating anything that tastes good, and I will exercise five times a week). Assemble the necessary motivations (e.g. accountability buddy, FitBit, bathroom scale, gym membership, workout routine, diet plan).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyman&#39;s Law</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/lymans-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 06:54:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/lymans-law/</guid>
      <description>A pretty-darned-optional part of being a software developer is getting a generally-applicable principle (a &amp;ldquo;law&amp;rdquo;) named after yourself. Most of the time, it seems, this happens unintentionally&amp;ndash;the law&amp;rsquo;s originator doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily foresee it becoming a pithy and oft-repeated internet adage. But if I could choose a principle to call &amp;ldquo;Lyman&amp;rsquo;s Law,&amp;rdquo; I think it might be this one:
 Code accompanied by unit tests will have a higher standard of code quality than code written without unit tests, even if the unit tests themselves are not taken into account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tech company scorecard</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/the-tech-company-scorecard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 08:15:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/the-tech-company-scorecard/</guid>
      <description>I’ve created this system for rating technology companies based on the way they conduct business, their place in the community and how they treat their developers. It’s a work in progress and I welcome your commentary.
There are 24 criteria under six categories. I would consider any company that scores positively on 12 or more of these criteria to be “a good place to work.” I have my doubts about whether any existing company could achieve a perfect score, so please don’t take it personally if your company comes up short in multiple areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction &amp; site info</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 11:16:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Hi. This is my personal blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll be migrating my posts from other platforms to this site.
I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer, a family man, a B.A. in English, and a Mormon. My writing is motivated by all of these things.
Comment Policy  Be pleasant. Keep it PG. Don&amp;rsquo;t advertise. Don&amp;rsquo;t hate.
 I welcome most forms of discussion and questions. That said: distasteful opinions, rudeness, and anything NSFW will be deleted on sight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steps to better code</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/steps-to-better-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 14:01:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/steps-to-better-code/</guid>
      <description>This is a chapter from Your First Year in Code, a book of practical how-to and advice for new developers. If you&amp;rsquo;re considering a career in software, check it out. It&amp;rsquo;s a free download at https://leanpub.com/firstyearincode.
When you start out coding, you usually spend a year or two completely oblivious to the rules of “good code.” You may hear words like “elegant” or “clean” tossed around, but you can’t define them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing a job title</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/choosing-a-job-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 13:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/choosing-a-job-title/</guid>
      <description>This is a chapter from Your First Year in Code, a book of practical how-to and advice for new developers. If you&amp;rsquo;re considering a career in software, check it out. It&amp;rsquo;s a free download at https://leanpub.com/firstyearincode.
Are you a coder, programmer, developer, engineer, architect or something else? My first job was an underage, under-the-table weekend gig at a pizza parlor. I’d show up at the local strip mall early Saturday morning, stash my bike, and clock in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 CSS gotchas to start your morning off right</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/8-css-gotchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 18:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/8-css-gotchas/</guid>
      <description>In every community there’s a coming-of-age process, a rite of passage that every newcomer must experience before he or she can really be considered an insider. For the CSS community, it goes something like this:
 Hey, this page is almost perfect. Can you just center that icon vertically? I told the boss we can roll it live in five minutes.
 For CSS junkies like me, lines like this provoke an involuntary nervous giggle, the kind of giggle you’ll hear if I tell you about the first time I got dumped or crashed my car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If doctors were like coders</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/if-doctors-were-like-coders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 23:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/if-doctors-were-like-coders/</guid>
      <description>Problem The patient has a broken leg.
Solution  Ask the patient to reproduce the exact scenario that resulted in the broken leg. Watch closely to see if the leg breaks again. Check for consistency by repeating the scenario a few more times. Explain that this isn’t an intended use case for the leg, and besides, it only affects one person. Ask the patient if, all things considered, he really wants to prioritize his broken leg over your other work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>America needs a new Republican party</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/america-needs-a-new-republican-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 12:19:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/america-needs-a-new-republican-party/</guid>
      <description>I’m a white man by birth and a Christian by heritage. I’m also a Democrat (technically unaffiliated, but only as an escape hatch). What’s more, I believe that I’m a Democrat because of my Christian heritage and beliefs, not in spite of them. It’s clear to me that the left side of America’s political divide most closely (albeit imperfectly) embodies the ideals of Judeo-Christian morality.
I feel a need to justify myself in this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>