<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Minimum Viable Blog</title>
    <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Minimum Viable Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2017 by Isaac Lyman. Site powered by Hugo and GitHub.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 11:16:33 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://isaaclyman.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction &amp; site info</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 11:16:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Hi. This is my personal blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll be migrating my posts from other platforms to this site.
I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer, a family man, a B.A. in English, and a Mormon. My writing is motivated by all of these things.
Comment Policy  Be pleasant. Keep it PG. Don&amp;rsquo;t advertise. Don&amp;rsquo;t hate.
 I welcome most forms of discussion and questions. That said: distasteful opinions, rudeness, and anything NSFW will be deleted on sight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer-driven development</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/developer-driven-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 04:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/developer-driven-development/</guid>
      <description>The company I work for is slowly losing its &amp;ldquo;startup&amp;rdquo; status. I’m trying not to be too nostalgic about it. After all, it means we’re doing well; a slew of truly impressive awards and contracts in recent months means we’re doing great. There’s a lot to be grateful for. At the same time, a lot is changing.
As this transition has played out, we’ve had to upgrade a few things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If doctors were like coders</title>
      <link>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/if-doctors-were-like-coders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 23:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://isaaclyman.com/blog/posts/if-doctors-were-like-coders/</guid>
      <description>Problem The patient has a broken leg.
Solution  Ask the patient to reproduce the exact scenario that resulted in the broken leg. Watch closely to see if the leg breaks again. Check for consistency by repeating the scenario a few more times. Explain that this isn’t an intended use case for the leg, and besides, it only affects one person. Ask the patient if, all things considered, he really wants to prioritize his broken leg over your other work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>